um
I
I'm excited about today's message
um because by the grace of God
this message is going to help somebody
to be prepared for the second coming of
Jesus
and so today we're going to be talking
about the millennium
and
rightly dividing the word of Truth the
Millennium and rightly dividing the word
of Truth
today is going to be a study
it's going to be an in-depth study
as to
understanding what the Millennium is
about as well as why so many people are
confused about it
so I hope you have something to take
notes with
um we're going to pray
and then we're gonna jump into the word
of God so let's do that now Heavenly
Father
bless us as we open your word
I pray Lord that you would preserve my
voice
I pray Lord that you would speak through
me
and I pray Lord that your word
will not return void
thank you Lord
for hearing and answering because we ask
it in Jesus name
amen
the Bible tells us
in the Book of Matthew
Jesus speaking
warns that if it were possible
at the end of time if it were possible
even the very elect
will be deceived and then he goes on to
to warn if they say Lo Christ is here or
low Christ is there believe it not
because as Lightning shines from the
East even onto the West so shall the
coming of the son of man be
I believe that
as the scripture points out many people
will be deceived at the end of time
and part of that will have to do with
this very teaching of the coming of
Christ
which
is very closely connected
to this understanding of the millennium
and what I believe is that because there
are so many people that do not
understand the millennium
there's going to be a mass deception
that is unlike this world has ever seen
and so we're going to go ahead and and
what we're going to do today is is a
little bit different if you've ever done
a study on the millennium
or heard me preach on the Millennium
what you're going to hear today is going
to be very different because what I want
to do first is I want to address the
reason behind the erroneous
understanding of the millennium
and to do that we're going to have to go
on a journey through the word of God so
that's what we're going to do and you
can you may be wondering Pastor why
aren't you teaching on
what happens in the Millennium I'm going
to be doing that towards the the the the
latter part of this message but
in order to understand
why people misunderstand this Doctrine
so much we've got to go through a
journey with the in the word of God
so we're going to go to the screen and
um please take notes take notes
the millennium
and rightly dividing the word of Truth
we're gonna go to the very beginning in
the Book of Genesis chapter 3.
we see that Adam and Eve have been put
out of the garden as a result of their
sin the Garden of Eden which itself
was like a paradise on Earth
So Adam and Eve are put out of this
Garden
and and that's in the Book of Genesis we
get to the Book of Exodus and we find
God in Exodus chapter 3 verse 8 we find
God speaking to Moses
and he's going to instruct Moses to lead
the children of Israel out of Egypt and
in fact in Exodus 3 verse say the Bible
says I am come down now to deliver them
out of the hand of the Egyptians and to
bring them out up out onto that land
onto a good land and a large onto a land
flowing with milk and honey now I want
to make sure y'all are following me and
I want you to note here that the
children of is that that God puts Adam
and Eve out of the garden and that's in
the Book of Genesis when we get to the
Book of Exodus the children of Israel
have been in captivity for 400 years and
God is now coming to deliver them out of
captivity and back into a special land
so I want you to think of this land very
similarly to how you would think of the
Garden of Eden
now let me break this down for you
because I want you to understand
the the
the
characteristics of this so-called
Promise Land
um let's go to I want to share with you
six characteristics of this promised
land so number one
this was to be a fruitful land in
Deuteronomy chapter 8 verse 7 the bible
says for the Lord thy God bring it thee
into a good land the land of Brooks of
water of fountains and depth that spring
out of valleys and Hills a land of Wheat
and barley and Vines and fig trees and
pomegranates a land of oil olive and
honey
a land wherein Thou shalt eat bread
without scarceness thou shall not lack
anything in it a land whose stones are
iron and out of whose Hills thou mayest
dig brass so imagine what kind of land
this must be right it almost sounds like
heaven this fruitful land that is going
to be producing things this fruitful
land that God himself is leading them
into it's called a Promised Land
so I want you to note once again kind of
like the miraculous nature of this land
okay let's go to the second promise long
life
in Deuteronomy 11 verse 8-9 therefore
shall you keep all the Commandments
which I command you this day that you
may be strong and go in and possess the
land whether you go to possess it and
that you may prolong your days in the
land
which the Lord swear unto your fathers
to give unto them and to their seed a
land that floweth with milk and honey
all right so do you all see that the
children of Israel would experience long
life in this land now let me ask you a
question
if I told you that there was a land you
could go to a country a nation you could
go to and in that Nation
the land itself produced bountifully and
by the way when you got there your
lifespan would expand you would live
longer how many of you would be
interested in going to a land like that
put a two in the chat if you'd be
let's keep moving number three
or let me keep reading uh let me look at
Deuteronomy 11 21 that your days may be
multiplied and the days of your children
in the land which the Lord swear unto
the fathers to give them as the days of
Heaven upon the Earth so so not only
were you promised long life but your
children would be promised long life
there would be no infant deaths
your children would live long lives are
y'all following so far all right let's
keep moving
number three
it was to be the glory of Nations it
shall come to pass if Thou shalt
diligently unto the voice of the Lord
thy God to observe and do all his
Commandments which I command you to stay
that the Lord thy God will set thee on
high above all nations of the earth and
all people of the Earth shall see that
thou art called by the name of the Lord
and they shall be afraid of thee so this
promised land was to was to have uh give
them long life not give them but they
would experience long life they would be
the they would be the glory of the
nations in other words nations would
look at them and say man what's going on
in that land
number four
they would experience no disease or
sickness
when the Lord thy God shall bring thee
into the land which the Lord which
wither thou goest to possess it and has
cast out many nations before thee that's
Deuteronomy 7 verse 1 then he goes on to
explain all these blessings and notice
what he says in verse in verse 15 and
the Lord will take away from thee all
sickness and I will put none of the evil
diseases of Egypt which thou knowest
upon thee so how many of you would like
to go to a land in which you don't get
sick you live long life the land is
Bountiful and all nations would be blown
away Amazed by what happens in that land
that sounds like heaven doesn't it
it kind of sounds like heaven it kind of
sounds like a heaven on Earth hence why
it was called the promised land let's
look at two more two more uh uh
conditions of this promised land in
Deuteronomy chapter 12 verse 10 but when
you go over the over Jordan and dwell in
the land which the Lord your God giveth
you to inherit and when he giveth you
rest from all your enemies round about
so that you dwell safely what we see
here is that this promised land was to
be a land where there was peace there
would be no war no conflict they would
have no need for swords they would beat
their plowshare their swords they would
they would not need any Weaponry because
of the Peace
that God would establish in that land
now I need y'all to be thinking very
carefully I'm going somewhere with this
and I cannot be excited as I want to be
right now because I am I'm trying to
maintain my voice all right so just
imagine my excitement imagine okay just
you know how I so just say that and I
want you to translate that into your
y'all need to get excited
because I'm about to explain something
to you that many people don't understand
and you need to follow this carefully
let's go to the last one the temple
the temple the temple was supposed to be
there
these are the statutes and judgments
which you shall observe to do in the
land which the Lord your God God of your
fathers giveth thee to possess it all
the days that you live upon the Earth
then there's more between that uh
Deuteronomy 12 and verse 5 but notice
verse 5 but unto the place which the
Lord your God shall choose out of all
your tribes to put his name there even
unto his habitations shall you seek and
thither Thou shalt come
and do this shall you bring your burnt
offerings and your sacrifices and your
tithes Etc so what we see here is that
God was saying I'm going to put my
habitation my name
in this place which was pointing to the
temple the temple long life there was
going to be no disease the land was
going to be fruitful they were going to
be the glory of the Nations I need you
to understand this this is why the
promised land was called the promised
land because of all these promises now
just put a seven in the chat if y'all
are with me so far all right put a seven
in the chat if you're following so far
y'all get this now I want you to
understand that there was a condition to
these promises put that word in the chat
for me there was a condition to these
promises in Deuteronomy 11 verse 26 the
Bible says here behold I set before you
this day a blessing and a curse a
blessing if you obey the Commandments of
the Lord your God which I command you
this day and a curse if you will not
obey the Commandments of the Lord your
God but turn aside out of the way which
I command you this day to go after other
gods which you have not known Leviticus
26 carries on and says I will make your
cities waste and bring your sanctuaries
into desolation and I will not smell the
savior of your sweet odors and I will
bring the land into desolation and your
enemies which dwell therein shall be
astonished at it so
the children of Israel were to
understand
that this land into which they were
going where all these promises were
supposed to take place were conditional
upon their obedience
are you following
notice with me Deuteronomy 28 16 61
moreover he will bring upon thee all the
diseases of Egypt which thou was afraid
of and they shall cleave unto thee also
every sickness and every plague which is
not written in the book of this law then
will the Lord bring upon thee until thou
be destroyed so you clearly see here
there were conditions to these promises
now what happened
well the children of Israel they get
into the promised land amen praise God
but when they get into the promised land
the question is do they obey God or do
they rebel against him the answer is
they rebel against him notice with me
Nehemiah chapter 9 verse 24 and 25 the
Bible says
so the children of Israel went in and
possess the land
and thou subdued before them the
inhabitants of the land the Canaanites
and gave them into their hands with
their kings and the people of the land
that they might do with them as they
would and they took strong cities and a
fat land and possess Houses full of all
Goods wells-daked Vineyards and oligars
and fruit trees and abundance so they
did eat and were filled and became fat
and delighted themselves in thy great
goodness nevertheless they were
disobedient and rebelled against thee
and cast thy law behind their backs and
slew the prophets which testified
against them to turn them to thee and
they wrought great provocation and so
the end result listen carefully to me
the end result is that they end up in
Babylonian captivity Second Chronicles
chapter 36 16-17 read but they mock The
Messengers of God
and despise his words and misused His
prophets until the Wrath of the Lord
arose against his people till there was
no remedy therefore he brought upon them
the king of the chaldees who slew their
young men with the sword in the house of
their sanctuary and had no compassion
upon young man or Maiden old man or him
that stood for age he gave them all into
his hands all right
put a seven in the chat if y'all are
following me so far we are just building
here to understand something absolutely
crucial
so here is where we have the rise of
various prophets Ezekiel
Isaiah
Jeremiah right it's in you you need to
understand the prophets in the context
of what is going on amongst God's people
God is sending these prophets because of
their rebellion in the promised land and
as a result of their rebellion in the
promised land they are not experiencing
long life
they're not experiencing the land being
fruitful why because they're disobeying
so much so that God brings them into
Babylonian captivity now when you read
the prophets Jeremiah Ezekiel or haggai
Joel uh uh um Isaiah you begin to
understand that what they were writing
about was in the context of the Promised
Land
are y'all with me so far
and so so so we had what we call
pre-exilic prophets and post-exilic
profits both profits made pre-exilitate
meaning the prophets that wrote before
Babylon destroyed Jerusalem and the
prophets that wrote after uh Jerusalem
was rebuilt restored and now waiting for
the coming Messiah so
I want you to notice how the pre-exilic
and also exilic prophets wrote about
this event of the destruction of Babylon
okay or the destruction of Jerusalem so
let's go back to the screen we're going
to go to the Book of Ezekiel we're going
to look at Ezekiel we're going to look
at Isaiah we're going to look at
Jeremiah but look at how Ezekiel
describes this
moreover the word of the Lord came unto
me saying also thou son of man thus
saith the Lord God the Lord God unto the
land of Israel and end the end is come
upon the four corners of the land now is
the End come upon thee and I will send
my anger upon thee and will judge thee
according to thy ways and will
recompense all the all that all the on
will recompense upon the all thine
Abominations okay
does Ezekiel sound like he's talking
about the end of the world
let me keep reading Ezekiel 7 7-12 The
Morning Has Come unto thee Oh thou that
dwelleth in the land the time has come
the day of trouble is near
and not sounding again of the mountains
behold the day
behold it is come
the morning is gone forth the rod has
blood has blossomed pride has budded the
time is come the day draweth near let me
ask you again
does it sound like Ezekiel is talking
about the end of the world
he's using
apocalyptic language now I need you to
understand here because just look let's
come back to the screen for a second
what I need you to understand here is
that Ezekiel even though he's using
apocalyptic language listen carefully to
me
he is not talking about the end of the
world
put a one in the chat if you understand
what I just said
even though Ezekiel is using apocalyptic
language he is not warning the children
of Israel about the end of the world
that it's to come thousands and
thousands of years he's not talking
about that to them
God has raised up Ezekiel to talk to the
children of Israel that's why you'll see
in the Book of Ezekiel speak unto the
children of Israel tell them that's
right Courtney what he's taught he's
using apocalyptic language to describe
the destruction of Jerusalem by Babylon
are y'all with me so far
let's let's just verify this in Ezekiel
12 13.
my net also will I spread upon him and
he shall be taken in my snare and I will
bring him to Babylon the land of the
chaldees and I will scattered toward
every wind all them that are about to
help him and they shall know that I am
the Lord when I shall scatter them among
the Nations and disperse them to the in
the country so here's what we see we see
Ezekiel using apocalyptic language to
describe the coming destruction of
Jerusalem by Babylon now let me ask you
a question if I were to read ezekiel's
words
and apply those words primarily to the
end of the world would I be rightly
dividing the word yes or no
I just need to make sure we understand
the destruction that Ezekiel is warning
about
is not the end of the world even though
at the end of time yes the world will
end
and and verses that are used that are
that diversity that we're looking in
Ezekiel can apply in a secondary sense
to the end of the world primarily what
is he talking about
he's talking about the destruction of
Jerusalem and he's using apocalyptic
language
let's go to the book of Isaiah Isaiah
we're going to see the same thing Isaiah
1 the vision of Isaiah the son of Amos
which he saw concerning Judah and
Jerusalem in the days of Uzziah jotham
ahaz Hezekiah and kings of Judah in
other words it tells you in the very
beginning of the book that the vision
that Isaiah sees is regarding Judah and
Jerusalem
let's keep going verse two hear o
heavens and give here give ear or Earth
for the Lord has spoken I have nourished
and brought up children they have
rebelled against me the ox knows his
owner and he asks his master's crib but
Israel does not know my people does not
consider verse for our sinful nation of
people laughing with iniquity a seed of
evil doers children that are corrupters
that have forsaken the Lord they have
provoked the Holy One of Israel unto
anger and they've gone away backward
your country is desolate your cities are
burned with fire your land strangers
devour it in your presence and it is
desolate as overthrown by strangers now
what is Isaiah talking about here is he
talking about the end of the world no
he's talking about the destruction of
Jerusalem notice Isaiah 2 verse 11 and
12.
the lofty looks of man shall be humble
and the haughtiness of men shall be
bowed down and the Lord alone shall be
exalted in that day for the day of the
Lord of hosts shall be upon everyone
that is proud and lofty and everyone
that is lifted up he shall be brought
low so come back
I need y'all to look at me here
is he Isaiah uses the term the day of
the Lord
now I got a question for you the day of
the Lord which is a day of Destruction
is Isaiah talking about the day of the
Lord at the very end of time is that
what he's warning the children of Israel
about
Beware of the day of the Lord at the
very end of time is that what he's doing
is that what he's doing
that's not what he's doing y'all the day
of the Lord in the context of Isaiah is
regarding the destruction of Jerusalem
by Babylon put a five in the chat y'all
if you follow what I'm saying if you
understand what I'm saying we need to
understand this and let me tell you why
because people are taking the reason why
people do not understand why they why
they fail to understand what is actually
going to happen in the millennium
is because they are using verses that
apply to the destruction of ancient
Jerusalem or to I'm gonna I'm not gonna
say that I'm just going to pause for a
second they're using verses that apply
to a situation back then and applying it
falsely
to what is going to happen in the future
they're using the Old Testament out
they're not rightly dividing the word of
God let's go back to the book of Isaiah
and I want you to note this Isaiah 24
verse 1. notice what the Bible says here
behold the Lord maketh the Earth empty
and maketh waste and turneth it upside
down and Scattered abroad the
inhabitants thereof the land shall be
utterly emptied and utterly spoiled for
the Lord has spoken it the Earth
mourneth and Faded the way the world
languages and faded away the hearty
people of the earth do language now come
back to the screen for a second
how many of you think that this verse is
primarily talking about the end of the
world
I'm just going to tell you that it's not
it is not talking about the end of the
world it is talking about the
destruction of Jerusalem and Isaiah is
using apocalyptic language if we don't
understand this beloved listen to me if
we don't understand this we are going to
make a very serious and deadly error at
the end of time
Isaiah is using apocalyptic language to
talk about the destruction of Jerusalem
how do we know just jump down with me to
verse 10. look at what the text says
the city of confusion is broken down
every house is shut up that no man may
come in in the city is left desolation
and the gate is smitten with destruction
let me ask you a question y'all what
city is he talking about because there
are millions of cities in the world why
would he use the word City singular the
reason why is because Isaiah who was
sent to preach to the children of Israel
is using apocalyptic language to
describe the destruction of Jerusalem
now Isaiah 24 has a secondary reference
yes to the very end of time but
primarily beloved primarily this text is
is talking about the destruction of
Jerusalem so let's keep moving
notice with me Isaiah 24 19 the Earth is
utterly broken down the Earth is clean
dissolved the Earth has moved
exceedingly the Earth shall reel to and
fro like a drunkard and shall be removed
like a cottage and the transgressions
thereof shall be heavy upon it and it
shall fall and not rise again verse 21
it shall come to pass in that day that
the Lord shall punish the host of the
high ones that are on high and the kings
of the earth upon the Earth and they
shall be gathered together as prisoners
are gathered in the pit and shall be
shut up in the prison and after many
days they shall be visited now let me
ask you a question how many of you have
read this text before
you've read this text before and you're
like oh yeah that's talking about
something at the end of time
beloved I need you to understand that
the primary meaning of this verse is the
destruction of Jerusalem by Babylon
and look y'all I'm not making this up
let me show you Albert Barnes commentary
on this very verse notice what it says
here
the senses that the rulers of the land
should be made captive and treated as
prisoners of War this was undoubtedly
true in the Captivity under
Nebuchadnezzar the people were assembled
were regarded as captives and were
conveyed together to a distant land let
me keep reading
where he says and shall be shut up in
the prison probably this is not intended
to be taken literally but to denote that
they would be
as secure as if they were shut up in
prison the prison house would be Babylon
where they were enclosed as in a prison
70 years and after many days if this
refers to not supposed to the Captivity
of the Captivity of Babylon then these
many days refer to the period of 70
years all right come back to the screen
do y'all see this
do y'all understand Ramona you're
already beating me to the punch you're
already getting to the punch line on
this when you said oh Jerusalem
Jerusalem listen y'all
the prophets of the Old Testament used
apocalyptic language to describe they
used the day of the Lord Motif to
describe the destruction of Jerusalem by
Babylon the reason I'm trying to set
this foundation so so uh uh um
clearly is because you need you have to
understand this to avoid the confusion
regarding the millennium
let's go to Jeremiah let's see if
Jeremiah does the same thing notice
Jeremiah chapter 4 verse 23 I beheld the
Earth and low it was without form
and void
and the heavens they had no light I
beheld the mountains and lo they
trembled and all the hills moved lightly
I beheld and lo there was no man and all
the birds of the heaven were fed now
you're like Pastor I am sure Jeremiah is
talking about the end of time here I
know he is
well let's keep reading
same chapter verse 26 I beheld and low
the fruitful places was a Wilderness and
all the cities were thereof were broken
down at the presence of the Lord and by
his Fierce anger for thus say the Lord
the whole land shall be desolate listen
to me y'all the whole land shall be
desolate yet will I not make a full end
what is Jeremiah describing here
was did Jerusalem become desolate and
yet not meet a full end
absolutely guys absolutely and let me
just
let me just show you here Jeremiah 4 4
29 the whole city shall Flee for the
noise of the horsemen and The Bowman
they shall go into thickets and climb
upon the Rocks every city shall be
Forsaken and not a man shall dwell
therein for I have heard a voice of a
woman in travail and the anguish as of
her that bringeth forth her first child
the voice of the daughter of Zion that
bewildered herself that spread with her
hands saying woe is me for my soul is
weary because of murderers who are the
murderers that she's going to be crying
about who else but Babylon Jeremiah is
using apocalyptic language to describe
the destruction of Jerusalem now watch
this
just so that y'all know I'm not making
this up if we go earlier up in the same
chapter look at what Jeremiah says in
verse 5.
he says declare you in Judah and publish
in Jerusalem and say blow ye the trumpet
in in the land cry gather together and
say assemble yourselves and let us go
into the defense cities set up the
standard towards Zion retire say not for
I will bring evil from the north and a
great destruction the lion is coming
from his ticket and the destroyer of the
Gentiles is on his way he has gone forth
from his place to make the land desolate
and thy City shall be laid ways without
an inhabitant all right
foreign
do y'all see here
that without a shadow of a doubt what
Jeremiah and Ezekiel and Isaiah are
doing as they're using apocalyptic
language they're using it to refer
listen carefully to me
not about the end of time
but about the destruction of Jerusalem
by Babylon they are speaking in
apocalyptic language but that
apocalyptic language is not to be
applied primarily to the end of time
all right
now I want you to know this Leviticus 26
verse 4 verse 40.
notice what God God put a clause within
this blessings and cursings he said
listen
if they shall confess their iniquity and
the iniquity of their fathers with their
trespass at which they have trespassed
against me and that also they have
contrary they have what contrary unto me
and that I also have walked contrary to
them and have brought them into the land
of their enemies if then their
uncircumcised Hearts be humbled and then
they accept of the punishment of their
iniquity then will I remember remember
my Covenant with Jacob and also my
Covenant with Isaac and I will also my
Covenant with Abraham while I remember
and I will remember the land
let's come back
what is God saying here
when I bring you into captivity Babylon
if you repent
what am I going to do
I'm going to remember the land
so here's what I want you to see let's
talk about how the prophets describe the
restoring of Jerusalem okay
let's see how they describe the
restoring of Jerusalem so let's go back
to Isaiah
chapter 1 verse 25 and I will turn my
hand upon thee and Purge away thy dross
and take away all thy tin and I will
restore thy judges as at the first
and by counselors as at the beginning
afterward thou shall be called the city
of righteousness the faithful City Zion
shall be redeemed with judgment and her
Converse with righteousness now come
back here let me ask you a question
how many of you think or have thought
when reading this verse that this was
applying to the very end of time
Jerusalem is going to be is going to
return to God and everything's going to
be good
put a one in the chat if that's you
if that was you
because I'm sure you understand right
now that what Isaiah is actually talking
about is not the restoration of the
world at the end of time or Jerusalem at
the very end of time he's talking about
their restoration from Babylon
the rebuilding of Jerusalem
are y'all with me
just give me a five minute chat if
you're like all right pastor we got you
we're following
so
with that in mind I now need you to
understand that when you're reading the
book of Ezekiel and when you're reading
the book of Isaiah and when you're
reading the book of Jeremiah and you see
these promises about this restored land
what is it not talking about
put that word in the chat for me please
what is it not
as in no what is it not talking about
it's a word I'm looking for and the word
is in the title of this sermon
it is the subject of this message
when they're talking about this restored
land they are not talking about the
Millennium y'all
they are talking about the restoration
of Jerusalem after its destruction of
Babylon so so
for example Isaiah 61 please note with
me Isaiah 61 verse 1.
when Isaiah writes a spirit of the Lord
God is upon me because the Lord has
anointed me to preach Good Tidings unto
the meek he has sent me the bind up the
Brokenhearted to Proclaim Liberty to the
captives and the opening of the prison
to them that are bound to proclaim the
acceptable year of the Lord and the day
of ventures of our God to comfort all
that mourn to appoint unto them that
mourn in Zion to give unto them Beauty
for Ashes the oil of joy for mourning
the Garment of Praise for the spirit of
heaviness that they might be called
Trees of Righteousness the planting of
the Lord that he might be glorified and
they shall build the old waste places
and shall raise up the former
desolations and they shall repair their
waste cities and the desolations of many
generations let me ask you a question
come back with me what is what is Isaiah
talking about here
he is not talking about some future
event in the middle he's talking about
the restoration of Jerusalem from he's
talking about those who have been
mourning in Babylon
that God is going to set them free and
rebuild their desolate places put a five
in the chat if you're following me if
you're if you're catching this so far
please now notice with me Isaiah 51
verse 11. you're gonna you're gonna see
this pattern notice with me Isaiah 51
verse 11. therefore the redeemed of the
Lord shall return and come with singing
unto Zion and everlasting Joy shall be
upon their head and they shall obtain
gladness and joy and sorrow and mourning
shall fill away this sounds
this sounds like Everlasting Joy oh
that's the end of the world that's the
Millennium no Beloved the the the the
the prophet is again using apocalyptic
language prophetic language to describe
the rebuilding of Jerusalem remember he
was sent to speak to the children of
Israel
tell them this and the prophets are
using a type of language to describe the
rebuilding of Jerusalem so now when we
come to Isaiah 51 verse 16 for example
notice what it says I have put my words
in thy mouth and I have covered thee in
the shadow of my hand that I may plant
the heavens and lay the foundations of
the earth and say unto Zion Thou Art my
people awake awake stand up o Jerusalem
which thought which has drunk at the
hand of the lord of the cups Fury and
thou has drunken the dreads of the cup
of trembling and rung them out no this
is this is deep y'all
this is almost my punch line here
come back to the screen
I have put my words in thy mouth and
I've covered thee in the shadow of mine
hand that I may plant the heavens and
lay the foundations of the Earth come
back here
this sounds like God is talking about a
new Heaven and a new Earth
put a one in the chat if y'all
understand what I just said
the text
sounds like God is talking about a new
Heaven
and the new Earth
however he is primarily Alisa listen
carefully to me
I see your question he is primarily the
primary application
is he's talking about the rebuilding of
Jerusalem as a new Heaven and a new
Earth
yes there is a there is a lot of
application but it is not the primary
application therefore if it is not the
primary application we can take some
things from the application but all
things in the application cannot apply
to what's happening in the future there
is another source that we must use as
the primary source for understanding the
Millennium and it is not these verses
does that make sense
these prophets were sent to speak to the
children of Israel so what's happening
is that because people are not rightly
dividing the word of truth they're
taking verses from the Old Testament
from Isaiah Jeremiah Ezekiel and trying
to apply those as primary
understanding for the Millennium which
you cannot do
because you're taking the text out of
its context
yes yes yes come on watch watch follow
me here follow me here notice notice
Albert Barnes again on the same verse
but the language here is evidently
entirely figurative it refers to the
restoration of the Jews to their own
land to the re-establishment of their
religion there to the introduction of
the new economy under the Messiah and to
all the great changes that would be
consequent on that this is compared with
the work of forming the heavens and
laying the foundations of the earth ah
man
are y'all catching this
there are verses that we're about to
look at that are that are in Isaiah and
in Jeremiah and in Ezekiel that people
have mistake because it's talking about
a new Heaven A New Earth they're going
oh that's the Millennium no
no
that's not the millennium that's talk
serration of Jerusalem and the promises
that would come back to them if they
were obedient the second time around
come Isaiah 51 verse 3 for the Lord
shall Comfort Zion he will Comfort all
her waste places and he will make her
Wilderness like Eden ah come on y'all
come on he will make her Wilderness like
Eden like the promised land hey remember
when I put man out of Eden in the
beginning listen if you are obedient to
me there is one who is coming
that if you accept him
your children
Will Not Die Young
you will not be able to be sick around
him
people are going to to wonder about the
blessings that are occurring in Israel
so I'm restoring you from Babylonian
captivity and listen if you are faithful
this time around the promised seed is
coming who when he comes
are y'all with me showcase Nation nurki
yes
when he comes if you do right your
nation is going to be the best Nation on
the planet
what about Ezekiel notice Ezekiel
Ezekiel 36 verse 35 Ezekiel agrees and
they shall say this land that was
desolate is become like the Garden of
Eden and the waste and desolate and
ruined cities are become fenced and are
inhabited Ezekiel is saying the same
thing that Isaiah is saying so when we
begin to see the prophecies about this
restored land people are mistakenly
taking those prophecies and applying
them to something they were not meant to
apply to come Jeremiah I want you to
know this Jeremiah 23 verse 20 verse 3
and 4. and I will gather the remnant of
my flock out of all the countries with I
have driven them and will bring them
again to their folds and they shall be
fruitful and increase and I will settle
Shepherds over them and which shall feed
them and they shall fear no more nor be
dismayed neither shall they be lacking
say the Lord watch this behold the days
come say the Lord that I will raise unto
David A righteous branch and a king
shall reign and prosper and shall
execute judgment and Justice in the
earth in his days Judah shall be saved
and Israel shall dwell safely and this
is his name whereby we he shall be
called the Lord our righteousness
therefore behold the days come say the
Lord that they shall no more say the
Lord liveth which brought up the
children of Israel out of the land of
Egypt but the Lord liveth which brought
up the children which brought up and
which led the seed of the House of
Israel out of the North country and from
all countries without whether I have
driven them and they shall dwell dwell
in their own land come come back with me
young
do you understand
that what the prophets
what the prophets are talking about here
is the restoration of Jerusalem and
what that Nation will be like
if
they receive this Branch this righteous
bread this seed of David remember those
promises long life
no disease let me ask you what did Jesus
do when he came was he healing people
what I need you to understand beloved is
so crucial
when we read these prophecies in the Old
Testament from Isaiah and Ezekiel and
Jeremiah and it's using this apocalyptic
language let me show you Isaiah 65 verse
17. listen to me y'all listen to this
for behold
for behold I create new heavens and a
new Earth the former shall not be
remembered nor come to mind but be ye
glad and rejoice forever in that which I
create for behold I create who
who
Jerusalem are rejoicing for our people
and I will rejoice in Jerusalem and joy
in my people and the voice of weeping
shall be heard no more in her
nor the voice of crying
there shall be no more dense an infant
of days nor an old man that has not
filled his days the child shall die a
hundred years old but the sinner being
accursed shut up being a hundred years
old shall be accursed and they shall
build houses and inhabit them and they
shall plant Vineyards and eat the fruit
of them they shall not build on another
inhabit they shall not plant and another
eat for as the days of a tree as are the
days of my people and minor let shall
long enjoy the work of their hands verse
23 they shall not labor in vain nor
bring forth trouble before they are the
seed of the Blessed of the Lord and
their offspring with them and then shall
come to pass that before they call I
will answer while they're yet speaking I
will hear the wolf and the lamb shall
feed together and the lion shall eat
straw like the Bullock and dust shall be
the Serpent's meat they shall not hurt
nor destroy in all my holy mountains
save the Lord now come on y'all come
back here for a second
go back to the screen
do you understand that this verse that
almost everyone takes to think oh he's
talking about the new heavens
the prophet Isaiah is using
apocalyptic language to describe the
restoration of Jerusalem particularly
if they receive the Messiah now now
watch this
if they receive the Messiah
if they accepted the Messiah
would their kids be sick would they
would their kids let's go back to the
screen
would the would there be an infant of
days
that died young
yes or no
would there be sickness and y'all need
to understand something here
what God is doing what God is saying
through the prophet
is that had they accept if they accepted
the Messiah
the healings
the the the the the the the blessings
even down to the wolf
and the land
here come back with me to the screen
what do you mean the wolf and the lamb
Pastor what are you talking about
remember Jesus said in Matthew 10 16
behold I send you forth as sheep in the
midst of wolves be there for wise as
serpents and homeless stuffs
the Sheep would be his own people the
Wolves would be those that didn't accept
him what God is telling us here is that
had Israel done right she would have
been the center of conversion for
righteousness so much so that wolves and
sheep would actually be able to dwell
together
in harmony
okay
Jew and Gentile
come back with me to the screen John
Gill
commenting on this verse says this the
wolf and the lamb shall feed together as
if they were one once of the same kind
of Nature and lived upon the same food
the people of God are comparable to
Lambs for their harmlessness and
innocent and wicked men to wolves for
their fierces and cruelty but by the
grace of God the latter becomes as mild
and as gentle as the former and live
upon the same spiritual food and join
with them in the attendance of the word
and ordinance
where they find spiritual refreshment
and comfort together such who have been
prosecutors persecutors of the church
shall now become members of it are y'all
with me
while Isaiah seems to definitely be
talking about the end of time he is
primarily listen to me y'all he is
primarily speaking about the restoration
of Jerusalem now I keep seeing the shot
but can it be dual can it be dual listen
y'all absolutely these verses are
shadows what word did I just use
there are shadows of what is to come in
the future but listen to me we need to
understand that the shadow is not the
actual reality
because when we go to the primary source
for the Millennium which is only found
in the Book of Revelation written by
John the prophet so watch this
do you realize that
The Book of Revelation was not written
how can I say this
God doesn't say in the Book of
Revelation speak unto Israel and say
he does with Isaiah he does with
Jeremiah he does all these other
prophets speak unto the children of
Israel and tell them this tell them that
the Book of Daniel and the Book of
Revelation are the only two prophetic
books which God specifically says these
books apply to end times
did y'all catch that
these books Daniel and revelation will
be unsealed at the end of time that's
not for you right now Israel
what's written in these books
by and large is not for you right now
it's for what unfolds
from the death of Christ all the way to
the end of time
so then listen carefully what I'm saying
for us to understand what happens in
Millennium when we jump to Isaiah and
Jeremiah and Ezekiel when you're if
you're studying with someone and they're
like well let me tell you what happens
in Millennium and they go to Isaiah
Ezekiel or Jeremiah they're you are
already on the wrong page you have
already started wrong oh there's going
to be a temple rebuild no y'all that was
talking about the rebuilding of the
temple you're after the Babylonian
destruction
that's not talking about during the
Millennium you got to go to the Book of
Revelation and see what does the Book of
Revelation say about the Millennium
because that's the primary source
Revelation uses allusions to the book of
Isaiah and Jeremiah Etc but we cannot
use the book of Jeremiah and Ezekiel and
Isaiah and and Zechariah as the primary
source to explain the Millennium so
that's why I beloved even amongst us and
you understand what I mean when I say
among us we look at these verses and
we're like man how do I explain that the
text says that a child will die will
children die in the Millennium no
children not dying in the Millennium and
we're going to see that when we get to
the Book of Revelation but the reason
why people think oh yeah there'll be
death in the book of in the in the
Millennium is because they go to Isaiah
and they look at the text and they say
oh this must be talking about the new
Heaven and new earth so yeah during the
Millennium there's going to be children
are going to die no
are y'all following me
so
uh uh let's go to the Book of Micah
and I want to show you what Michael says
now it shall come to pass in a latter
days that the mountain of the Lord's
house shall be established on the top of
the mountains and shall be exalted above
the hills and people shall flow to it
many nations shall come and say come let
us go up to the mountain of the Lord to
the house of the god of Jacob he will
teach us his ways we shall walk in his
past for out of Zion the law shall go
forth and the word of the Lord from
Jerusalem he shall judge between many
people and rebuke strong Nations afar
off they shall beat their swords into
Power shares and their Spears into
pruning hooks Nations shall not lift up
sword against Nations neither shall they
learn War anymore but everyone shall sit
under his Vine and under his fig tree
and no one shall make them afraid for
the mouth of the Lord has spoken it now
let me let me break this down for you
and I know y'all thinking
Pastor are you going to talk about
Revelation 20. I am I'm getting there
I'm getting there but I need you to
follow this Micah Micah is talking about
the promise of a restored Jerusalem he's
talking about because if you read the
the next chapters in The Book of Micah
you see him talking about one who is
going to be born in Bethlehem he's
talking about these promises and what we
need to understand is that this promise
of beating your swords into into
plowshares and that all the nations will
come to to Jerusalem and say let us go
up to the mountain of the Lord all of
that would have been based on their
acceptance of Jesus as the Messiah
are y'all following this
are y'all catching this
come on let's keep moving let's go to
the Book of Ezekiel and I want you to
know about Ezekiel notices and and
Ezekiel 37 21 say unto them thus saith
the Lord God behold I will take the
children of Israel from among the
Heathen whether they have been gone and
will gather them on every side and bring
them into their own land
and I will make them one nation in the
land upon the mountains of Israel and
one King shall be king to them all and
there shall be no more two Nations
neither shall they provided to be
divided into two kingdoms anymore
neither so they defile themselves
anymore with their Idols nor their
detestable things nor with any of their
transgressions but I will save them out
of all their Dwelling Places wherein
they have sinned and will cleanse them
so they shall be my people and I will be
their God who is the king he's talking
about that's going to rule over them
they're talking about the coming of
Jesus let's keep reading and David my
servant shall be king over them and they
shall have one Shepherd they shall also
walk in my in my judgments and observe
my statutes and do them and they shall
dwell in the land that I've given unto
Jacob my servant where on your fathers
have dwelt and they shall dwell therein
even they and their children and their
children's children forever my my
servant David shall be their prince
forever verse 26 moreover I will make a
new a covenant of peace with them and it
shall be an Everlasting Covenant with
them and I will place them and multiply
them and will set my sanctuary in the
midst of them forevermore and my
Tabernacle shall also be with them yea I
will be their God and they shall be my
people and the heathens shall know that
I the Lord do sanctify Israel When My
Sanctuary shall be in the midst of them
forevermore all right come back to the
screen
come back to the screen
one of the biggest one of the most
egregious errors when it comes to what
people believe about the Millennium is
they talk about ezekiel's Temple
ezekiel's Temple this Temple that
Ezekiel is talking about is going to be
built in the future is going to be in
the listen y'all
listen
Ezekiel just described to us
the coming of this King under David my
servant that is Jesus and then God says
I will set my temple in the midst of
them what I need you to understand is
when Ezekiel is describing this temple
in chapters 40 to 48 it is not some
future Temple that's going to be rebuilt
that's not what he's talking about what
he was talking about was the rebuilding
of the actual Temple
after the Babylonian destruction God is
going to rebuild a temple now you're
saying pastor that doesn't quite add up
why would Ezekiel describe this temple
in this way with all this description
watch this
when the temple was finally rebuilt
listen to what the book of Ezra says
but many of the priests and Levites and
chief of the fathers who were ancient
men that had seen the first house when
the foundation of this house was laid
Before Their Eyes wept with a loud voice
and many shouted aloud for Joy so that
the people could not discern the noise
of the shout of Joy from the noise of
the Weeping of the people for the people
shouted with a loud shout and the noise
was heard afar off why are they shouting
and crying listen because some of them
were totally depressed
come back with me
they know that Ezekiel has prophesied
this glorious Temple but when they see
it they're like this isn't what the
prophet Ezekiel described to us
and that's why they're weeping now come
on y'all follow me with this
come with me to the book of haggai
notice what the prophet haggai says who
is left among you that saw this house in
her first glory and how do you see it
now is it not in your eyes in comparison
of it as nothing yet now be strong also
rubidou say the Lord and be strong o
Joshua son of Joshua the high priest and
be strong all you people of the land say
the Lord and work for I am with you say
the Lord of hosts watch this according
to the word that I covenanted with you
when you came out of Egypt so my spirit
remains among you fear ye not for thus
say the Lord of hosts yet once in a
little while and I will shake the
heavens and the earth and the Sea and
dry land and I will shake All Nations
and the desire of all Nations shall come
and I will fill this house with Glory
say the Lord of hosts come on y'all
come on
the temple that Ezekiel is describing
is in fact
Jesus himself
he is the glory that that's why God is
like look you see this Temple it's not
like it was before you heard what
Ezekiel said but what I'm trying to help
you to see and understand is that the
temple Ezekiel is talking about is So
Glorious because the glory of God is
going to fill that Temple
that's why John 1 14 says and the Word
was made flesh and dwelt among us and we
beheld his glory the glory as of the
only begotten of the father full of
grace and truth that's the temple
Ezekiel 40-48 is talking about and this
is why Jesus said in John 2 19 Jesus
answered and said unto them destroy this
Temple am I in three days I will raise
it up the Jews said 46 years was his
template in building and will you rare
it up in three days but he spake of the
Temple of his body are y'all catching
this
are you following this
so check this out this is why Jesus come
back here I I need to break this down
before I read this verse
when Jesus comes
he understands
the blessings that God had for Israel
but because they reject him
because they reject the Messiah Jesus is
now about to weep watch watch what he
says and when he was come near he beheld
the city and wept over it saying if thou
hath known
even thou at least in this day the
things which belong unto thy peace but
now are they hidden from your eyes
they shall lady even with the ground and
thy children with thee and shall not
leave in thee one stone upon another
because you knew not the time of your
visitation come back come back with me
do you see the case that I just made
Israel would have been the glory of the
world had they accepted the Messiah
nobody would be sick the land would be
would be a land formed with milk and all
the promises God had given back there in
Deuteronomy would have been realized and
the world would have been like yo man
talk about Taurus people would be going
to Israel from everywhere
but remember this was an if then thing
the blessings and the curses which one
do you want
they chose the curses
so now that we understand listen
carefully now that we understand the
primary meaning of the prophecies in
Zechariah and Isaiah and Jeremiah and
all these different places now that we
understand that now now we can come to
the place where we're like okay well in
order for me to understand the
Millennium then
there's only one source that I can begin
with and that is the Book of Revelation
The Book of Revelation must be the
primary source and now guys we're just
going to run through them now that I've
set this out the way
we're just gonna run through the we're
going to see how simple and easy this is
to understand so please I'm going to ask
you give me
give me just a little while longer
because I'm not going to spend a lot of
time hiring out it becomes once that's
out of the way it becomes very easy to
understand the Millennium so come follow
me I promise you I'm not going to keep
you much longer okay so just follow me
here in John 14 1 Jesus said let not
your heart be troubled you believe in
God believe also in Me In My Father's
House of many mansions if it were not so
I would have told you I go to prepare a
place for you and if I go and prepare a
place for you I will come again and
receive you unto myself that where I am
there you may be also so come back with
me follow this very carefully
Jesus just told the disciples that he's
going somewhere
and that they can't go with it now but
he's going to prepare a place and the
place is going to prepare when he comes
he's going to come again and receive
them so that they can be with him now he
didn't say I'm coming back to be with
you he said I'm coming back to take you
to be with me so the question is where
is this place that Jesus is going where
the he's going to the father well
where's the father Luke 11 2 and he said
unto them when you pray say Our Father
which art and where Heaven very good
y'all got it so if the father's in
heaven and Jesus says I'm going to go to
prepare a place for you where in heaven
that I'm coming back to take you with me
where I am I'm not coming to be with you
yet I'm coming to take you where I am so
what event describes this
first Thessalonians chapter 4 13.
I would not have you to be ignorant
Brethren concerning them which are
asleep or dead that you saw or not even
as others have no hope for if we believe
that Jesus died and rose again even sold
them with sleep in Jesus will God bring
with him
remember Jesus said I'm coming to take
you with me you will be with me Jesus
will bring your God will bring with him
what is what does the text telling us
when Jesus comes again
he's coming to take his people to go
with him to heaven
this is where the Millennium occurs and
we're going to see that when we get over
to the Book of Revelation but I need you
to follow this verse 15 for we this we
say unto you by the word of the Lord
that we which are alive and remain unto
the coming of the Lord shall not prevent
them which are asleep for the Lord
himself shall descend from heaven with a
shout with the voice of the Archangel
and with the Trump of God and the dead
in Christ shall rise first then we which
are alive in remain shall be caught up
caught up not caught down but caught up
together with them in the clouds to meet
the Lord in the air not on the ground in
the air and watch this so shall we ever
be with the Lord come back with me so
shall we be with the Lord where is the
Lord he's in heaven we're going to be
with him he's not coming to be with us
where we are he's taking us with him put
a one in the chat if you're following
so so watch the righteous Matthew 24 30
then shall appear the son of the son of
man in heaven then some all the tribes
of the earth mourn and they shall see
the son of man coming in the Clouds Of
Heaven with power and great glory and he
shall send his angels now why is he
sending his angels if he's coming here
if he's coming to set up the Millennium
on Earth why is he sending his angels no
he sent his angels with a great son of a
trumpet and they shall gather together
his elect from the Four Winds from one
end of the Heavens to the other so come
I need y'all to catch this
listen carefully
the Millennium
does not occur on Earth
those promises in Isaiah and Jeremiah
and Ezekiel were were regarding almost
like the setting up of a of a mini
Kingdom of Heaven in Jerusalem had the
people of Israel accepted the Messiah
but they don't and now watch this the
only two prophets that God has given us
to primarily discuss the the the the the
the the the plan of the Millennium is
the prophets Daniel and Revelation and
primary or Daniel and John and primarily
John
so now I got to go over to John and say
okay since that plan of Israel becoming
this glorious place that failed not
because of God but because of the people
now God says here's what's going to
happen in the millennium
are y'all with me
Jesus is going to come
he's his feet are not touching the
ground not yet
he's going to come he's going to call
the Saints up with him watch this come
with me to Revelation 20 verse 1. and I
saw an angel come down from heaven
having the key of the bottomless pit and
a great chain in his hand and he laid
hold on the dragon that old serpent
which is the devil in Satan and bound
him a thousand years this is the
Millennium watch this and cast him into
the bottomless pit and shut him up and
set a seal upon him that he should
deceive the Nations no more they say
Pastor it says Nations right there
deceive the Nations no more hold on
we're going to find out why
it says till the Thousand Years should
be fulfilled and after that he must be
loose a little season now watch this I
saw Thrones and they sat upon them and
judgment was given unto them and I saw
the souls of them that were beheaded for
the witness of Jesus and for the word of
God and which had not worshiped the
Beast neither his image neither had
received his Mark upon their forts or in
their hand and they lived and reigned
what's that word y'all
they lived and reigned
with Christ
a thousand years they are with him where
he is
listen
what happens to the righteous when Jesus
comes again
both the righteous living and the
righteous dead will be caught up
together in the clouds to meet the Lord
in the air where they will spend a
thousand years with the Lord
the reason why there's a thousand years
of peace on Earth is because the wicked
are dead on the earth while the the
nations of the saves are in heaven with
God that's why there is peace on the
earth for a thousand years in fact I
want you to notice the different
translations of the last verse I just
read they came to life and reigned with
Christ a thousand years they will come
to life and Rule with Christ a thousand
years they came to life they came back
to life they came to life they came to
life they came back to life beloved this
is talking about the resurrection of the
righteous
Jesus comes again the writers are
resurrected they go up to be with the
Lord in the air Isaiah 26 19 thy dead
men shall live together with my dead
body shall they rise awake and sing ye
that dwell on the Dust for the dues of
the Dew of the herb and the Earth shall
cast out the Dead I want you to notice
what I just did
all we're doing here is we're going to
Isaiah as a secondary source that keeps
in line with what's happening in
Revelation chapter 20.
do you see what we just did rightly
dividing the word
we stay in Revelation we understand what
what John the Revelator is saying and
then we can go back to the Old Testament
and look at verses that amplify that not
why is it so important because I need
you to check this out
come with me come with me to Revelation
uh um Revelation 20 verse 5. notice what
the Bible says here but the rest of the
Dead live not again until the thousand
years were finished this is the first
resurrection blessed and holy is he that
has part in the First Resurrection on
such the second death has no power but
they shall be Priests of God and of
Christ and shall reign with one thousand
years come I got a question for you
according to this text
come back to the come back come back I
need you to see me here according to
this text the primary verse for us to
understand the Millennium will there be
death during the millennium
will people be dying during the
millennium
the answer is no
the righteous have gone to heaven the
wicked perished at the coming of the
Lord and those Wicked Dead who died
years and thousands of years before they
don't live again that's why the text
says the rest did not live again until
the thousand years have finished so all
the wicked are dead all the righteous
are in heaven will people be on earth
dying will kids be on earth dying at 100
years old
no do y'all understand what just
happened
people
would rather go to Isaiah and say Yes
children will be dying in the Millennium
why because look at Isaiah he's talking
about the new Heaven and the new Earth
and if he's talking about the new heaven
the new Earth then it's obvious there's
going to be death during the millennium
that's what they do
instead of understanding that these
verses are not primarily talking about
they're primarily talking about the
restored kingdom of Jerusalem and what
would have happened if Jesus came and
they accepted him so so yes can we go
back and say yes the wolf and the lamb
will live together yes we can take that
application and put it over in
Revelation can we say uh uh will there
be yes we can take those applications
and put but we cannot take the part that
says children will be dying at 100 or
people will be alive we can't do that
because the primary source is revelation
and according to Revelation the
righteous go to heaven while the wicked
remain dead
you understand that the Bible says as it
was in the days of Noah so shall it be
in the days of the son of man so what
happened in the days of Noah when when
when when the art was built and the door
was closed all who were outside the ark
died there was no Second Chance all who
were in The Ark were saved it's going to
be the same thing when Jesus comes again
when he comes again the wicked are are
are are killed they're destroyed by the
brightness of this coming while the
righteous are caught up in the ark they
are caught up to Christ to live with him
for a thousand years
look at this we're almost done y'all we
are we are literally almost done we're
almost done
notice with me verse seven and when the
thousand years are expired Satan shall
be loosed out of this prison and shall
go out to deceive the Nations which are
in the four quarters of the earth Gog
and Magog to gather them together to
battle the number of whom is as the sand
of the sea why where these people come
from
they've been resurrected
at the end of the Thousand Years the
reason why Satan is again able to
deceive the Nations is because the
wicked had been brought back to life
the wicked happened bro see he has an
army again
and it's all his people it's all his
seed
so how do we know this watch this the
Bible says in verse 9 and they went upon
the breath of the earth and compassed
the camp of the Saints about and the
Beloved City and fire came down from God
out of heaven and devour them beloved
this happens at the end of the 1000
Years where did the city come from
you'll see
come with me
Revelation 21 verse 2 and I John saw the
holy city New Jerusalem coming down from
God out of Heaven prepared as a bride
adorned for her husband so according to
the text beloved according to the text
it is at the end of the Thousand Years
that the New Jerusalem
comes down because God is now going to
place it on Earth
because that's going to be the new
Dwelling Place he's going to recreate
Heaven and Earth he's going to put the
New Jerusalem here on this Earth at the
end of the Thousand Years and beloved
what people are thinking is
they're taking these verses from the Old
Testament and applying them to the
Millennium thinking oh when Jesus comes
again he's going to set up his kingdom
on Earth which beloved happens to be the
very same deception that led to the
people of God back then rejecting Christ
because they thought that when Christ
came it was actually going to be heaven
on Earth
so their misunderstanding of Isaiah and
Jeremiah and Ezekiel that exact
misunderstanding LED them to reject the
Messiah yes Michelle and Zachariah when
you read the entire book of Zechariah
you are reading about he's talking about
the coming of the Messiah and he's doing
the same thing Ezekiel is doing he's
talking about this restored condition of
Jerusalem if they would accept the
Messiah
so then watch this
if Jesus when he comes again doesn't
touch the ground
and if Jesus said take heed that no man
deceive you if Jesus said if it were
possible even the very elect would be
deceived why because people are going to
say Lo here is Christ you know what that
tells us that tells us that Satan
himself is going to attempt to
counterfeit the coming of Christ Satan
himself is going to attempt to to to to
come as if he were Jesus and because
people don't know that when Jesus comes
again he's not touching the ground he's
staying in the sky and calling the
people up because they think when the
Messiah comes he's going to set up a
kingdom on Earth for a thousand years
beloved who do you think who do you
think is going to come in and try to
fill that spot I'm here
I am the Messiah and I'm ready to set up
my kingdom on Earth and by the way
those who will not go along
those who will not go along with this
new righteous Kingdom on Earth they are
the wicked ones and we need to kill them
that's why Jesus said 11 the time is
coming were they that kill you will
think they are doing God a service
foreign
this is why context matters
so beloved with all of that what are we
called to do we're called to be ready
for Jesus's Second Coming
I know what we did today was a very kind
of cerebral like understanding okay
pastor I get it now I understand but
listen if you understand but you're not
ready for the coming of the Lord what
difference does it make
the same the same mentality that led the
children of Israel to reject the Messiah
back then because they weren't prepared
they didn't understand and they weren't
prepared is the same thing that will
lead to the rejection of the true Christ
when he comes they're thinking he's
coming in a different way they're
thinking he's coming to set up a kingdom
on Earth and I want to be a part of that
Kingdom beloved that's a set up for the
devil
that's a setup of the devil
so Christ is inviting us all ye that
that that that they come on to me and I
will give you rest I stand at the door
and knock he's trying to say I want you
to be ready for my coming and I don't
want you to be deceived by the enemy I
don't want you to be deceived by false
teaching that's why living Nana is here
beloved to to to by the grace of God be
the channel a channel one of many
channels that that can facilitate the
The Taking of Heaven's matter and
bringing it down to
the people
I always remember this listen this
understanding you understand this you'll
be able to go back to the Old Testament
go all I I get it now ah I I see it now
you'll read Zechariah you will read
Ezekiel you will read Isaiah and you'll
begin to ah I understand I now I get it
now I understand
so Jesus is really asking
are you ready are you getting ready for
my coming
are you getting ready for my appearing
because that's the most important thing
that is the most important thing are you
be are you preparing yourself
to be ready when I come again
so I want to make a simple appeal right
now you may be watching you you may have
never never given your life to Christ
before
and I'll make appeal right now
I'm gonna make an appeal right now that
if you have not given your life to the
Lord and you're saying okay you know
what like I don't even know why I was
watching this today but I watched it and
man I just learned some stuff I need to
understand more I want to be ready when
Jesus comes again I I want to be
prepared for that coming if that's you
I'm going to ask you put in the chat yes
Lord yeah put in the chat put in the
chat that one to say yes Lord I need to
be I need to give my life to you I've
been wrestling with this decision to
give my life to you and I'm giving it to
you now I'm giving it to you today if
you're watching in the chat and that's
not you but you're saying you know what
I have been way I've given my life to
the Lord but I've fallen away and I need
to be I need to get back on track I need
to get back to following him and being
because I don't want to be deceived like
they were deceived back then that I want
you to put that two in the chat and say
that's me I see the ones I see the ones
praise God for you listen I'm going to
ask all of you putting down ones right
now I'm gonna ask you to get into touch
with our Bible worker I want you I we
want to pray for you either get in touch
with our Bible worker if we can put
those links in the chat for our prayer
team for our Bible worker for Rick
I want you to get a hold of us right we
want to pray for you we want to we want
to we want to pray that your walk will
be what it needs to be
when you decide to follow Christ for
those of you who are putting the two in
the chat
praise God for you praise God
for coming back
for Desiring to get your heart back on
fire with God
listen y'all
our world is getting crazier and crazier
like literally I mean I know our world's
always been crazy but it's getting
really crazy y'all it's getting really
crazy and the more time goes on the
deeper we need to get into the word of
God you know like just
preaching for entertainment like that is
it's not doing anything for anybody we
need living manner yeah we need living
bread
we need to understand the craziness
going around us and we need to
understand ourselves and what we need to
do to get ourselves right through the
grace of God so I I just praise God for
every decision made here for those of
you who are saying hey you know I'm
interested in living matter I want to
get into Bible studies I want to
understand what it is that you teach and
and what you believe we're going to put
out the the contact of our Bible work
it's right up on the screen get send the
email we'll we'll pair you up with a
Bible worker and we will walk with you
through this process all right
so beloved God bless you by the way if
there's someone that needs to be
baptized
if there's someone that's realizing
today you know what I've been putting
this off I need to be baptized I need to
give my life fully to the Lord I need to
dedicate my life for it to the Lord
please reach out to our Bible worker and
we will we will we will work with you in
that process as well all right
God bless you guys let's pray heavenly
father thank you for speaking to us
thank you Lord for opening up the word
thank you Lord for preserving my voice
and thank you Lord for for for raining
down truth today
Lord may we never look at the Bible the
same
may we may we grow closer to you may we
get a greater understanding of who you
are and what you desire of us Lord and
our father we just thank you
ascending your son into this world
to redeem us
thank you Lord that we will get to spend
a thousand years in heaven with you
Lord please
speak draw close to us draw near to us
Lord
and we thank you for hearing and
answering this prayer because we ask it
in Jesus name amen I want to say the
thought actually just um as I was
praying I thought about this just if you
continue reading through the Book of
Revelation chapter 20 you will see that
the week the reason that the wicked are
resurrected at the end of time is
because God is going to explain to them
his judgment
so if you read Revelation 20 the last
few verses it says the books were open
and the dead were judged out of those
books and then they were cast into the
Lake of Fire so the wicked are destroyed
at the very end of time we have a share
the truth playlist on living Mana um
YouTube channel as well as the Paragon
YouTube channel and I go through several
different teachings state of the Dead
Hellfire ever the second coming they
these all tie in together so if you miss
those and you need to go that way I need
to understand about this and that Etc go
back and find that playlist Maybe we can
put it in the chat here
um and as we're doing that
as we're doing that I'm going to invite
you to join us on altar live okay
um we'll put the link for also live in
also live is where we have our Afterglow
where we discuss Sabbath school and we
discuss the sermon uh and we share your
thoughts so please we we would love to
have you join us uh in Ultra live for
our after-ball discussion
um there the link is in the chat
God bless you
pray for my voice
because
yeah
it's starting to go again
but I'll be all right that'll be all
right uh yeah if we can put that
playlist in the chat that would be that
would be great and uh God bless you guys
I will see you over on alter
live when this goes off we'll leave it
up for a little bit so we can get that
link for this uh the playlist in the
chat
um so that for those of you that want to
watch you can you can do so
thank you thank you for worshiping with
us today if this is your first time
visiting with us we invite you to check
out our website at livingmana.live there
you will learn more about our mission to
reach the world with the Gospel of Jesus
we have exciting life programs
throughout the week covering topics like
physical health mental health prayer
learning how to prove God's existence
and much more if you would like to
support the ministry you can click on
the tithe and offering link on our
website we ask that you continue to pray
for the church as God continues to open
doors for our programming to reach the
world thank you again for your prayers
and your support
thank you